So we're going to start our exploration into the world of frontier models by playing with the famous
그래서 개척자 모델의 세계를 탐구하기 위해 오픈AI의 유명한 GPT를
GPT from OpenAI, which most of you are probably quite familiar with.
사용해 볼 겁니다 여러분도 잘 알고 계시겠죠
I have a pro license, which means I get access to all of the models, and I imagine some of you do
전 프로 라이선스가 있어요 모든 모델에 엑세스 권한이 있다는 뜻이죠 여러분도
as well.
그럴 거예요
We'll start with a softball question, the kind of question that they're so good at answering, which
소프트볼 질문으로 시작하겠습니다 그들이 아주
is how do I decide if a business problem is suitable for an LLM solution?
잘 대답하는 질문이죠 사업상의 문제가 LLM 해결책에 적합한지 어떻게 결정할까요?
And it's useful for us because it's the kind of question that one might ask on this course.
이 강의에서 물어볼 만한 질문이라 우리에게 유용하죠
And what we'll get back, of course, is a very carefully structured and reasoned response with an introduction,
그리고 나서 아주 조심스럽고 합리적인 구조를 갖춘 답변을 해 줍니다. 요약본을 제공하고
with summaries, the nature of the problem, the scalability needs.
문제의 본질과 확장성 문제를 설명하죠.
No doubt there'll be stuff in here about nuance, about unstructured data, contextual understanding,
뉘앙스와 비구조적인 데이터 맥락적 이해 비용, 유지보수
cost, maintenance, lots of great, well-reasoned points with a good summary to boot.
논리적인 요점들과 훌륭한 요약도 들어 있어요
So this is the kind of thing that it's really, really good at.
이런 게 정말 잘 되는 거죠
Now I'll ask it a question, which it usually gets right, but sometimes amazingly gets wrong.
이제 질문을 할게요 보통은 맞지만 놀랍게도 틀릴 때도 있어요
Let's see what happens this time.
이번엔 어떻게 될지 보죠
How many times does the letter A appear in this sentence?
A가 이 문장에 몇 번이나 나오죠?
Uh, so let's see how it does.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
Uh, it's got it wrong.
잘못 만들었어요
The letter A appears five times in your sentence.
A는 형량에 다섯 번 등장해요
Sometimes it gets this right, and sometimes it gets it wrong.
잘 될 때도 있고 안 될 때도 있죠
It's, uh, difficult to know, but.
알 수 없는 일이죠
But, uh, it might shock you that, uh, it gets that wrong.
하지만 잘못되면 충격받을 거예요
It doesn't mean that we humans still have an advantage in some ways.
그렇다고 인간이 여전히 유리한 점이 있다는 건 아니에요
But the truth is, it's to do with the way that this information is sent into the LM.
하지만 사실은 이 정보가 달 착륙선으로 전송되는 방식과 관련이 있어요
It's to do with this, this tokenization strategy.
토큰화 전략과 관련이 있어요
And we'll be talking more about that later.
그 얘긴 나중에 더 하죠
But it is interesting that it gets it wrong.
하지만 틀리다니 흥미롭네요
Uh, I'm going to ask it one more question, which is a tricky question.
어려운 질문이지만 하나만 더 물어볼게요
I'm going to ask it, uh, Choose the word that best completes the analogy.
질문을 할 건데 이 비유를 가장 잘 완성하는 단어를 고르세요
Feather is to bird as scale is to.
새에게 깃털은 비늘과 같아요
And then there's a few different options there.
몇 가지 다른 옵션이 있어요
And the best answer is in fact, reptile fish is a bit of a trick answer because fish do have scales,
정답은 파충류 어류입니다 사실 어류도 비늘이 있어서 정답이라고 할 순 없지만
but it's not as distinguishing feature as it is for reptiles.
파충류에 비해 비늘이 특이한 기능은 아니죠
This question I got from a website called vellum, which is a very a company that does a lot of this
이 질문은 벨럼이라는 웹사이트에서 받았어요 이런 종류의 분석을 많이
kind of analysis that we will talk about later.
하는 회사인데 나중에 얘기하도록 하죠
All right.
좋아요
Let's switch to a different model.
다른 모델로 바꿔볼게요
Let's switch to zero one preview.
01 프리뷰로 넘어가죠
This is the model that was originally codenamed strawberry and is the strongest of OpenAI's models,
원래 코드명이 딸기였던 모델입니다 오픈아이에서 가장 강력한 모델로 프로 구독자만 사용할 수
only available to Pro subscribers, but it will ultimately be available to everyone, and it gives you
있지만 궁극적으로는 모두가 사용할 수 있습니다 앞으로 어떤 모델이 나올지
a sense of what's to come.
감이 오실 거예요
It uses a sort of chain of reasoning approach to think through questions.
일련의 추론 접근을 통해 질문을 통해 생각해내죠
Let's ask it the same question how many times does the letter A appear in this sentence.
같은 질문을 해 보죠 A라는 글자가 이 문장에 몇 번 나오죠?
See if it can do better.
더 잘하는지 보죠
It's thinking.
생각 중이에요
You can see how it takes longer for sure.
얼마나 오래 걸리는지 아시겠죠?
Counting letter frequencies.
문자 주파수를 세고 있어요
That sounds promising.
조짐이 좋은데요
Taking a closer look.
자세히 살펴보죠
Good to know.
좋은 정보네요
And it gets the right the answer.
정답을 맞힐 수 있어요
Correct.
맞아요
The letter A appears four times in the sentence.
A는 문장에 네 번 등장하죠
Once in many, uh, once within the quotes and twice in the word appear.
많은 경우에 한 번은 따옴표 안에 한 번은 단어에 두 번 나타나요
So it is correct.
맞는 말이네요
Very good.
좋아요
Uh, and then let's also ask strawberry.
그리고 딸기한테도 물어보죠
Oh, one preview this, uh, this puzzle and let's see how it can approach this.
이 퍼즐을 미리 보기하고 어떻게 접근하는지 보죠
It's considering choosing the right analogy that's also promising cultivating.
적절한 비유를 선택하는 것도 배양의 장래성이죠
And it gives the correct answer reptile.
정답을 알려줍니다 파충류예요
So this gives you a sense of the different models, some of the different strengths between them from
이렇게 하면 다양한 모델과 GPT 40과 01 프리뷰의
GPT four zero and zero one preview.
장점을 알 수 있죠